adirondacksolutions.com 2016-12-27

# Adirondack Solutions

**Introduction**

Adirondack Solutions respects your privacy. We have created this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to demonstrate our firm commitment to online privacy. This "Notice of Privacy Policy" discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for certain of Adirondack Solutions’s Websites, which include Adirondack Solutions.com Privacy Policy applies to all information that you provide to Adirondack Solutions and that Adirondack Solutions maintains electronically, whether you provide the information through the Adirondack Solutions Web Sites or through other means. Additionally, this Privacy Policy applies to any personal information obtained from your use (and, if applicable, your family's use) of the Adirondack Solutions Web Sites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that you may provide to third parties; for example, other sites linked to the Adirondack Solutions Websites. You should contact such third parties directly to determine their respective privacy policies. As used herein, the terms "Adirondack Solutions," "we," "our" and "its" when referring to Adirondack Solutions, Inc. and its related companies are used only for convenience and are not intended to be an accurate description of ownership, operation or corporate/legal relationships.

**What information does Adirondack Solutions collect?**

If you are an employee or client of Adirondack Solutions, we collect and maintain a variety of personal information about you and, if applicable, your employer. This information may be collected through the Adirondack Solutions Website or through paper forms submitted by you. For employees, the information we maintain includes, among other things: 

  * your name, phone number and address (street and e-mail)
  * age, marital status and occupation
  * information about your job history and employment status
  * information about your salary and benefits, including health benefits, your time off, your retirement plans, your Social Security or taxpayer identification number
  * your recruiting and training history
  * information about your family members such as their names, addresses and Social Security numbers

**What is this information used for?**

We use your personal information in the course of your employment or client relationship with Adirondack Solutions. For example, we allow you to edit and update personal information online. We also use your information for other things, which may include but is not limited to the following:

  * **Contacting You**  
Adirondack Solutions uses your personally identifiable information to communicate with you in the course of your employment or client relationship. While we must be able to contact you for matters relating to your employment or your client relationship, if you do not wish to receive e-mail communications from Adirondack Solutions regarding strategic alliance offers or other third-party products and services, you may opt out of receiving such communications by following the procedure set forth in such e-mail. Adirondack Solutions will continue to contact you for matters relating to your employment or your client relationship. IP addresses are numbers that are automatically assigned to your computer, and if associated with other individually identifiable information, could be considered personal information. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer and improve the Adirondack Solutions Web Sites. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information, some of which we aggregate and then share with our strategic alliances or potential strategic alliance companies. We also use your IP address to keep track of the information you have seen on our sites.
  * **Other General Information**  
If you send us your resume, we use that information to assist you with job placement. 

**With whom is this information shared?**

Adirondack Solutions shares personal information only as described below:

  * **Your Worksite Employer**  
If you are an employee, most of your personal information is also available to your individual worksite employer. However, Adirondack Solutions does not provide information regarding your physical and/or mental health to any third party for any purposes, unless compelled by a governmental or legal authority.
  * **Governmental Authorities, Compliance with Law and Protection of Adirondack Solutions and Others** We provide information to governmental authorities when required to do so by law (for example, we report information regarding your compensation and withholding to the U.S. Internal Revenue Service and state taxing authorities). Adirondack Solutions will also provide personally identifiable information to third parties if compelled to do so by an appropriately empowered governmental or legal authority, or, as necessary, to protect Adirondack Solutions's rights or the rights of third parties.
  * **Benefit Plan Providers**  
Adirondack Solutions will also provide personally identifiable information to its third-party benefit providers in conjunction with the administration of its benefit plans.
  * **Medical Emergencies**  
If necessary to respond to an apparent medical emergency, Adirondack Solutions may disclose selected employee information.
  * **Business Transfers**  
As Adirondack Solutions continues to develop its businesses, it may sell various aspects of its business. If Adirondack Solutions sells a portion of its business, it will transfer personal information associated with that business as part of such a sale. Also, in the unlikely event that Adirondack Solutions or substantially all of its assets are acquired, personal information regarding employees and clients will be one of the transferred assets.

**What access do you have to information you provide?**

You have access to much of your personal information through the Employee Service Center, where you can view and update most of the personal information we maintain.

**Security measures**

Adirondack Solutions makes access to your personally identifiable information subject to certain security measures, including technological controls such as "firewalls," in accordance with industry standards. When the use of the Adirondack Solutions Web Sites involve the transmission of confidential information about you or Adirondack Solutions, we use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to establish a secure connection between your PC and our server. SSL allows the transmission of encrypted information from your PC to our server and back again and is the industry standard for Internet platform security. No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, so while Adirondack Solutions strives to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to Adirondack Solutions.

**Safe harbor Compliance**

Adirondack Solutions, Inc. complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. Adirondack Solutions, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Adirondack Solutions, Inc. certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

**Disclaimer of responsibility for privacy policy and content at linked sites**

The Adirondack Solutions Web Sites may provide you with links to other Web sites. We are not responsible for those sites and cannot control the use of information that you submit once you reach those sites, nor can we control the content of what is offered on those sites or on links from those sites. You should contact such third-party Web sites directly to determine their privacy policies.

**This is not a children’s Web site**

Adirondack Solutions does not knowingly solicit data from children, and we do not knowingly market to children.

**Changes in these policies and practices**

Adirondack Solutions reserves the right to change its privacy policies and practices periodically, without providing individual notice, by updating this Privacy Policy notice. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 1/14/2014. You agree that it is your responsibility to monitor such updates. Your continued use of any of the Adirondack Solutions Web Sites after such revisions have been made or your failure to object in writing to any notice of such change will constitute your full acceptance of such revised Privacy Policy.

**California Residents - Your Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family or household use to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to the address provided at the end of this Privacy Policy. Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the Section 1798.83 requirements, and only information on covered sharing for California customers will be included in our response.

**More information**

In accordance with California Civil Code § 1786.20, the representative named above will be able to assist you with additional information regarding our privacy practices or policies in the event of a compromise of your information.
